Register of the Laurence H. Silberman Papers, 1947-1976
Hoover Institution Archives
- UNITED STATES DEPARTMENT OF LABOR, 1959-1975 (Box 8-45)
  - Economic stabilization. Primarily relates to the activity of the Nixon Administration Cost of Living Council
    - Price Commission. Background material for meeting, regulations and a statement, 1971 Nov.-1972 April (Folder 9)
  - Emergency disputes
    - General. Clippings, 1970 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Legislation
      - "National Emergency Public Interest Protection Act of ", 1970
        - General. Reports, memoranda, letters, printed material, proposals, notes, press release. Includes materials relating to the Railway Labor Act and the Taft-Hartley Labor Act, 1969 June-1970 Feb. (Folder 2-5)
        - Draft legislation. Includes cover memorandum, 1970 Jan.-Feb. (Folder 6)
      - "Emergency Public Interest Protection Act of ", 1971
        - General. Memoranda, letters, reports, bills, notes, meeting minutes, and speech transcripts (Richard Nixon and Laurence Silberman), 1970 Sept.-1971 Nov. (Box 25, Folder 1)
        - Notebook. Collected materials including bills, speeches (Richard Nixon, Laurence Silberman), reports, memoranda and miscellany, ca. 1970-1971 (Folder 2)
      - "Crippling Strikes Prevention Act of 1972". Reports, notes, memoranda, testimony (James Hodgson and others), letters, resolutions, speeches, press conference transcript and press releases, draft and printed copies of bills; includes material relating to a West Coast dock strike, 1972 Feb.-Oct. (Folder 3-4)
  - Employment development programs
    - General. Letters, reports, testimony (George Shultz) and memoranda, 1969 June-1972 Nov. (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Emergency Employment Act
      - General. Memoranda and letters, 1971 March-1972 Nov. (Folder 2)
      - Status reports. Reports to White House staff (Charles Colson and Paul O'Neill), primarily relating to fund allocation, 1971 Sept.-1972 Jan. (Folder 3)
    - Manpower Administration
      - General. Memoranda, letters, directories, planning and budget reports; includes a copy of the Manpower Development and Training Act of, 1962, 1962-1972 (Folder 4-5)
      - Notebook. Relates to major policy issues of FY, 1972, 1970 (Folder 6)
      - Notebook (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Public Employment Programs. Letters, memoranda and report, 1971 Jan.-1973 Jan. (Folder 2)
    - Unemployment. Testimony transcript, correspondence, memoranda, report, and clipping, 1970 Jan.-1972 Oct. (Folder 3)
  - Equal employment opportunity (formerly the Employment Standards Administration)
    - General
      - General
        - General. Reports, memoranda, meeting notes, directory, letters, miscellany and a printed copy of the Civil Rights Act of, 1964 (Folder 4-5)
        - Notebook. Testimony relating to the Equal Employment Opportunity Act of 1971 (S. 2515), ca. 1971 March-Oct. (Folder 6)
        - Notebook (Box 28, Folder 1)
      - Bureau of Apprenticeship and Training (BAT). Memoranda, corrrespondence, audit report, regulations, minutes of a meeting with the AFL-CIO, and charts, 1970 April-1972 March (Folder 2)
      - Office of Federal Contract Compliance (OFCC) (Folder 3)
        - General. Memoranda, newsletter, statement, printed material, findings and decision, answers to questions from the Senate Labor Committee; relates to housing, a conference, a case involving Bethlehem Steel, and other, 1970 Jan.-1973 Jan.
        - EEOC-Office of Federal Contract Compliance. Proposed transfer of function
          - General. Printed article, memoranda and a report, 1970 (Folder 4)
          - Notebook. Collected materials relating to testimony before the House Committee on Education and Labor, the House Armed Services Committee and the Senate Committee on Labor and Public Welfare, ca. 1971 March (Folder 5)
    - Age. Memoranda, correspondence, and a legal decision, 1972 May-Oct. (Folder 6)
    - Religion/national origin. Memoranda, correspondence, statement and printed material primarily relating to Jewish affairs, 1970-1972 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Women
      - General. Regulations, memoranda, printed article, report, press release and correspondence, 1969 March-1973 Aug. (Folder 2)
      - Guideline revision. Draft and printed copies of regulations, memoranda, press releases, printed material, reports, statements (including George Shultz, Edward Kennedy and Edmund Muskie), notes and letters, 1970 April-1971 Dec. (Folder 3-5)
  - Handicapped. Letters and a press release, 1971 Jan.-1973 Jan. (Folder 6)
  - Health care industry. Letters, reports, meeting materials and miscellany, 1971 April-1972 Oct. (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - International labor and commerce
    - General. Speech transcripts, correspondence, briefing material, memoranda and materials relating to visits by foreign officials, 1969 July-1973 March (Folder 2)
    - Council on International Economic Policy
      - Memoranda, 1971 Oct.-1975 Jan. (Folder 3)
      - Reports
        - "The United States in the Changing World Economy,", 1971 July (Folder 4)
        - "A Foreign Economic Perspective,", 1972 Feb. (Folder 5)
    - Trade adjustment assistance. Reports, memoranda, letters, notes, press release and regulations, 1972 Jan.-Nov. (Folder 6-7)
  - Labor relations
    - General
      - General. Memoranda, agenda and draft legislation, 1969 May-1972 May (Box 31, Folder 1)
      - Public employees
        - General. Printed articles, directory, conference materials and a report, 1969-1972 (Folder 2-3)
        - Federal policy. Pamphlets, notes, reports, statement and memoranda primarily relating to personnel reorganization, protest activities, executive management and civil service
          - 1969-1970 Sept. (Folder 4-5)
          - 1970 Sept.-Nov. (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Labor law
      - General
        - General. Serial issues, printed articles, reports, and a speech transcript, 1969 April-1972 Aug. (Folder 2-4)
        - National Labor Law Institute. Proceedings from a conference, including a presentation by L. Silberman, 1970 May (Folder 5)
      - Labor-Management Act of, 1959
        - General. Draft and printed copies of legislation, reports, memoranda, letters, legal documents, printed materials, press release, notes, executive order and miscellany, 1959-1972 (Box 33, Folder 1)
        - Investigations. Legal documents, report, chart and letter, SEE ALSO: Pension plans, 1969. (Folder 2)
      - National Labor Relations Board
        - General. Printed articles, correspondence, research proposal, and a report, 1969 June-1973 Nov. (Folder 3)
        - Appointments. Memoranda and letters of recommendation, 1971 (Folder 4-5)
  - Maritime industry
    - General. Report, memoranda, correspondence and agenda, 1969 Dec.-1972 Nov. (Folder 6)
    - Compensation. Draft and printed copies of legislation, letters, statements, reports, memoranda and miscellany relating primarily to proposed amendments to the Longshoremen's and Harbor Workers' Compensation Act of, 1972, 1970 March-1973 Jan. (Folder 7)
    - Strikes. Primarily International Longshoremen's and Warehousemen's Union
      - General. Correspondence, reports, notes, press releases, memoranda, draft and printed copies of resolutions, draft and printed copies of legislation, statements and printed materials. SEE ALSO: Emergency disputes
        - 1971 March-1972 Jan. (Folder 8)
        - 1972 Feb.-Dec. (Box 34, Folder 1)
      - Reports
        - "Impact of Longshore Strikes on the National Economy,", 1969 Oct. (Folder 2)
        - "Report to the President,", 1971 Oct. (Folder 3)
  - Minimum wage. Reports, memoranda, statements and charts, 1971 April-1972 Oct. (Folder 4-6)
  - Nixon administration. NOTE: Most of the materials originated by the White House have been arranged topically
    - General
      - General. Speech transcript (Daniel P. Moynihan), press conference (John Connally), and memoranda, 1970 Dec.-1972 Dec. (Box 35, Folder 1)
      - Conferences. Printed material, 1972 Feb. (Folder 2)
      - Correspondence
        - Agnew, Spiro T., 1971 Sept.-1972 Sept. (Folder 3)
        - Colson, Charles, 1973 July (Folder 4)
        - Ehrlichman, John, 1973 Feb.-March (Folder 5)
    - Government reorganization. Reports, letters, briefing material, printed article and memoranda, 1968 Nov.-1972 March (Folder 6)
    - Responsiveness program. Correspondence with the Justice Department and others, memoranda, testimony transcript, and meeting notes, 1972 June-1974 July (Folder 7)
  - Occupational Safety and Health Administration
    - General. Meeting material, drafts and printed copies of legislation, reports, notes, charts, miscellany, policy papers, press releases, statement, regulations, briefing material and printed material
      - 1969 May-1971 Oct. (Folder 8-10)
      - 1972 Jan.-Sept. (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence and memoranda
      - General, 1970 Dec.-1972 Nov. (Folder 2)
      - Labor Department. Primarily internal memoranda; also includes planning materials, reports, legal opinions, printed materials and draft regulations, 1970 Dec.-1972 Nov. (Folder 3-4)
      - Other government agencies, 1970 Oct.-1972 Aug. (Folder 5)
      - U.S. Congress, 1970 Nov.-1972 Oct. (Folder 6)
    - Notebooks. Relates primarily to the development of legislation, 1969-1970 (Box 37, Folder 1-5)
  - Pensions
    - General
      - General. Printed articles, speech transcripts (Richard Nixon and others), reports and a memorandum, 1967-1972 (Box 38, Folder 1)
      - Reports, including a report of the activities of a joint Labor-Commerce task force on pension benefit security, 1969-1972 (Folder 2-3)
    - Legislation. Primarily amendments to the Welfare and Pension Plans Disclosure Act
      - General. Reports, memoranda, draft legislation, notes, legal documents, statements, petition, speeches, testimony and press conference transcripts
        - 1968 Sept.-1971 May (Folder 4-7)
        - 1971 June-1972 Nov. (Box 39, Folder 1-3)
      - Bills. Drafts and printed copies, 1962-1972 (Folder 4)
      - Correspondence, 1970 Dec.-1972 Nov. (Folder 5)
      - Notebook. Comparison of S.2, H.R. 1269 and H.R. 16462 (Folder 6)
  - Research and policy development (ASPER). Memoranda, letters and reports; includes material prepared for a Labor Department conference, 1970 Dec.-1972 Nov. (Box 40, Folder 1-2)
  - Transportation industry
    - General. Memoranda and correspondence, July 1970-1972 Nov. (Folder 3)
    - Railroads
      - General. Memoranda, reports, correspondence, statement, chronology, resolution, and draft and printed copies of legislation relating primarily to collective bargaining and the Railpax Act, 1963 Aug.-1971 Feb. (Folder 4-5)
      - Reports
        - "The Railroad Shopcraft-Carrier Labor Dispute,", 1967 (Folder 6)
        - LMSA-ASPER-Solicitor Task Force on Railroad Employee Adjustment Provision,", 1972 (Folder 7)
    - Teamsters. Letters and memoranda; includes a letter from James R. Hoffa, 1969 Oct.-1973 Dec. (Folder 8)
  - United Mine Workers
    - General. Memoranda, printed materials, meeting report, legal documents, and notes, 1963 May-1971 Aug. (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Elections
      - 1969 Dec.
        - General. Correspondence, a draft copy of an article, draft legislation, and a meeting report, 1969 May-1973 April (Folder 2)
        - Complaints, pre-election
          - Correspondence with Joseph Yablonski and his attorney, Joseph Rauh, 1969 July-1972 April (Folder 3)
          - Notebook. Collected materials, primarily duplicate correspondence, 1969 Aug.-1970 March (Folder 4)
        - Justice Department investigation. Primarily collected material including reports, election results, allegations, legal documents, correspondence and chronologies, 1969-1972 (Folder 5)
        - Litigation
          - General. Legal documents, printed material, memoranda, chronologies, notes and letters, 1970 July-1972 Aug. (Box 42, Folder 1)
          - Notebook. Collected legal documents, ca. 1970 March (Folder 2)
      - Collected material, primarily correspondence, relating to pre-election complaints, 1970 Aug.-Dec., 1970 Dec. (Folder 3)
      - Reports, memoranda and press releases, 1972 June-Nov., 1972 Dec. (Folder 4)
    - Finances. Correspondence, memoranda, printed material, legal documents, and reports, primarily relating to pension plan administration and litigation, 1963 Dec.-1972 May (Folder 5)
    - Senate investigations
      - General. Newsletters, chronologies, statements, printed material, notes and reports, 1963-1970 (Box 43, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence, 1970 Jan.-1972 March (Folder 2)
      - Transcripts, 1970 Feb. 5-March 20 (Folder 3-7)
  - Veterans. Memoranda, correspondence, and a press release, 1971 Jan.-1972 Nov. (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Vocational education. Memoranda and letters, 1970 Sept.-1971 March (Folder 2)
  - Welfare reform
    - Meeting material
      - General. Memoranda, 1971 July-Oct. (Folder 3)
      - Belmont Opportunities for Families (OFP) conference. Letter, memoranda, miscellany, and policy reports; primarily collected material, 1971 Oct. (Folder 4-5)
      - Regional meetings. Reports, memoranda, statements, miscellany and other background material, 1971 May-June (Folder 6)
    - Memoranda, 1969 April-1972 Oct. (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Reports, 1969 April-1972 Oct. (Folder 2-5)
  - Workers' compensation programs. Correspondence and memoranda, 1971 Jan.-1972 Nov. (Folder 6)
  - Yugoslavia. Memorandum and printed material, primarily relating to trade unions and an international seminar, 1969 Dec.-1971 Sept. (Folder 7)
- UNITED STATES JUSTICE DEPARTMENT, 1947-1976 (Box 46-50)
  Procedure manual, appointment calendars, biographical sketches, map, itineraries, agenda, reports, legal documents, printed material, miscellany, correspondence, memoranda, lists, press releases, forms, telephone logs, clippings, draft and printed copies of legislation, proclamations, executive orders, regulations and speech transcripts. Related to specific anti-trust cases, Watergate, government reorganization and oversight, illegal aliens, drug enforcement, and other issues. Arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - General
    - General. Procedure manual, biographical sketches, directory, map, clipping, itinerary, agenda and reports, 1947-1973 (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - Appointment calendars, 1974 March-1975 April (Folder 2)
    - Correspondence
      - Official
        - General
          - General. Includes printed material, legal documents and other miscellany, 1974 March-1975 March (Folder 3)
          - Invitations, 1974 March-1975 Feb. (Folder 4)
        - United States Congress. Relates to discrimination, illegal drugs, draft evasion, pending legislation, surveillance activities, and other, 1974 March-1975 March (Folder 5)
        - White House. Memoranda and correspondence relating to the INS, energy policy, litigation, and the CIA, 1973 Feb.-1975 Feb. (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Personal
        - General. Includes clippings and letters of recommendations; includes letters from William Saxbe, Donald Rumsfeld, Elliot Richardson, Edward Kennedy, Charles Mathias, Jr. and Richard Kleindienst, 1973 Oct.-1975 April (Folder 2)
        - Congratulations. Includes letters from Frank Carlucci and Donald Rumsfeld, 1974 Jan.-June (Folder 3)
    - Memoranda, 1974 March-July (Folder 4)
    - Personnel materials
      - General. Miscellaneous applications, forms and memoranda, 1974 March-1975 April (Folder 5)
      - Confirmation. List, press release, and hearing transcripts, 1974 Feb.-March (Folder 6)
      - Conflict of interest inquiries. Memoranda and correspondence primarily relating to general policy, 1971 June-1974 March (Folder 7)
    - Telephone logs, 1974 March-June (Box 48, Folder 1-5)
  - Attorneys. Memoranda relating to detailing attorneys to the White House, 1974 March (Folder 6)
  - Border study. Reports, letters (Gerald Ford and others), clippings, and memoranda relating to illegal immigration and drug enforcement, 1974 March-1975 March (Folder 7)
  - Campaign Reform Act of 1974. Report, press release, and draft legislation, 1974 March (Folder 8)
  - Central Intelligence Agency. Meeting agenda and reports, ca. 1975 March (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Clemency Board. Memoranda, correspondence, proclamation, executive order and report relating to pardons for draft evaders, 1974 Sept.-1975 Jan. (Folder 2)
  - Drug Enforcement Administration
    - General. Clippings, memoranda, statements by Senator Henry M. Jackson, correspondence with Senator Charles Percy and others, 1975 June-1976 April (Folder 3)
    - Transcript. Testimony of L. Silberman before the Senate Permanent Committee on Investigations, 1975 July 15 (Folder 4)
  - Electronic surveillance. Memoranda, and printed material, 1974 Feb.-May (Folder 5)
  - Ford, Gerald R. Correspondence between Robert Bork and Congress relating to the FBI investigation of Gerald Ford, and press releases relating to policy, 1973 Oct.-1974 Dec. (Folder 6)
  - Hughes, Howard. Memoranda relating to potential extradition and litigation, 1974 June-Sept. (Folder 7)
  - Immunity. Memoranda, correspondence and report, 1971 Sept.-1974 July (Folder 8)
  - International Telephone and Telegraph (ITT). Report relating to anti-trust litigation, 1972 (Folder 9)
  - Judges. Memoranda and letters primarily relating to appointments, 1974 June-1975 Jan. (Folder 10)
  - Nixon, Richard M.
    - Impeachment. Report, correspondence with Peter Rodino, Jr., and memoranda, primarily relating to requests for information, 1974 Feb.-May (Folder 11)
    - Papers. Memoranda, legal documents, reports, correspondence with Arthur Sampson, Richard Nixon and others, draft legislation, and wire reports primarily relating to the custodianship of the Nixon presidential papers, 1969 March-1974 Nov. (Folder 12)
  - Reorganization. Notes, correspondence with Elliot Richardson and others, memoranda, regulations and reports, 1973 Nov.-1974 May (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - U.S. v. I.B.M. Reports, memoranda, legal documents, and correspondence, primarily with Nicholas Katzenbach, relating to anti-trust litigation, 1972 Dec.-1975 March (Folder 2)
  - Watergate. Correspondence with Howard Baker, Leon Jaworski and others, reports, memorandum, legal documents, speech transcript (Richard Nixon) and a press release, 1974 March-Oct. (Folder 3)
- PHONOTAPES.
  - One phonotape recording entitled, "Bessie Margolin Farewell Dinner," Emceed by L. Silberman, 1972 January 28. (Oversize Tape cabinet)
- PHOTOGRAPHS.
  1 print of Laurence Silberman and Mrs. Silberman with Senator Hugh Scott at the swearing-in ceremony of Mr. Silberman as Under Secretary of Labor, 1970; 2 prints of participants in a Dept. of Labor conference at San Clemente, 1970; 1 inscribed print of Lester Maddox, 1972; 2 prints of an unidentified conference group, circa 1970; 1 print of a White House meeting with Vice President Agnew.